<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning on Nikhil Thota</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/tags/learning/</link><description>Recent content in Learning on Nikhil Thota</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilthota.com/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Like Riding a Bike</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/riding-a-bike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/riding-a-bike/</guid><description>Something that has always astounded me is the vast amount of information tucked away in some corner of our minds, out of reach. We&amp;rsquo;ve all spent our entire lives engaged in some activity or another and provide our brains a constant stream of input. A small percentage of this input sticks, while most seemingly disappears. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t believe this data is completely gone — it&amp;rsquo;s merely hidden.
Biologically, our brains are complex and messy.</description></item><item><title>The Discomfort Index</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/discomfort/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/discomfort/</guid><description>This is an experiment. I refuse to be limited by the tantalizing decree to write something perfect or fully fleshed out every time I have an idea. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent months procrastinating on this piece because I felt like it had to be perfect, when something short and to the point would have sufficed.
When attempting something new, discomfort is unavoidable. From building an exercise routine to quitting a bad habit, discomfort is necessary.</description></item><item><title>Multimodal Reading</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/multimodal-reading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/multimodal-reading/</guid><description>Books are incredible. They&amp;rsquo;re even better when you can get them for free. However, one thing that I struggle with is figuring out what to read with the vast quantity of options available. One thing that has helped me is segmenting my reading into buckets based on the medium of consumption.
What does that mean? Today, there are more ways to read a book than to just buy a physical tome and read it cover-to-cover.</description></item><item><title>Libby: Free Knowledge</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/libby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/libby/</guid><description>havin&amp;rsquo; fun ain&amp;rsquo;t hard&amp;hellip; if you got a library card
August 21st, 2019 was an interesting day for me. It was an average wednesday, except that I had just gotten an audiobook copy of When Breath Becomes Air by Paul Kalanithi. Being the 2x playback speed fiend that I am, I made it to the end in a couple of days and found myself tearing up in the gym in between sets of incline bench press.</description></item></channel></rss>