<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Health on Nikhil Thota</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/tags/health/</link><description>Recent content in Health on Nikhil Thota</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilthota.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Self Experimentation Protocol</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/self-experimentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/self-experimentation/</guid><description>This was originally posted on my newsletter.
This past month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been chowing down on globs of spirulina, chlorella, and other nutritious micro-algae every day. I&amp;rsquo;m sane I swear — these algae are some of the most dense and bioavailable sources of protein &amp;amp; nutrients available. There is also some promising research showing that they might protect the brain and improve metabolic function.
A problem innate to health &amp;amp; nutrition research is that the human body is finicky, and what benefits one person will not necessarily benefit another.</description></item><item><title>What happens when you don’t eat for 72 hours?</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/fasting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/fasting/</guid><description>Alla Hetman
Hey everyone. Before we get into this, I am not a medical professional (sorry dad). Everything that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is based on personal experience and publicly available information. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering doing an extended fast, do your own research. ✌🏽
A couple of months ago, my marathon-running-roommate Kenton convinced me, my other roommate Tyler, and my girlfriend Mack to attempt a 72 hour fast with him.</description></item><item><title>The Philosophy of a Dairy Pill</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/dairy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 14:14:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/dairy/</guid><description>Lactose Intolerance [ lak-tohs in-tol-er-uh ns ] / noun — a digestive disorder caused by the inability to digest lactose, a main carbohydrate in dairy products, which can lead to a negative effect on quality of life. A very common disorder, with some groups estimated to have a 79% rate of affliction.
It was a lovely, brisk Sunday evening in Seattle. Autumn was imminent, so the leaves had recently shifted to a more varied palette of rustic earth tones.</description></item><item><title>Sleep as a Service (SaaS)</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sleep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 14:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sleep/</guid><description>I recently finished Matthew Walker’s Why We Sleep, a New York Times Bestseller which has been exploding in the productivity-obsessed circles that I’m a part of. For good reason too — this book distills the vast amount of modern sleep research over the past 20 years into one main idea: sleep is really important. In the past year or so, I’ve been experimenting with everything in the sleep-improvement space, from blackout curtains to melatonin to timing my caffeine consumption (all of these being small but integral pieces of the puzzle).</description></item></channel></rss>