<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nikhil Thota</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/</link><description>Recent content on Nikhil Thota</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 23:50:08 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilthota.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Untethered Soul</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/untethered-soul/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 23:50:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/untethered-soul/</guid><description>15808 NW 90th Street, Alachua, Florida, 32615 — The Temple of the Universe
Nested in the thicket of North Florida&amp;rsquo;s wilderness, about a 30 minute drive from the University of Florida, is the Temple of the Universe. The temple is a spiritual sanctuary where &amp;lsquo;men and women of any religion or set of beliefs can come together to experience the love, peace, and bliss which exists within all beings.</description></item><item><title>Disjointed Fellowship Fragments</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/interact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 23:50:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/interact/</guid><description>A few months ago, I applied to the Interact Fellowship, but unfortunately got rejected shortly after. The application essays however, were incredibly insightful and posed a lot of interesting questions that I found myself thinking a lot about. I wanted to share my ramblings for some of these questions because I think that they tell a lot about who I am as a person. Shoutout to Kenton for the idea.</description></item><item><title>On Frugality and Flourishing</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/frugality-flourishing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 14:15:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/frugality-flourishing/</guid><description>It’s February, and I have a yearning to finally finish this piece. I’ve been putting it off for so long, but it’s time that I actually attempt to press some keys and create some prose. This is a topic I feel is especially relevant these days as I’ve been having interesting conversations and thoughts about money and the value of frugality. If my first several months into the world of true financial independence as a fully fledged ‘adult’ is any signal, I am obsessed with saving money.</description></item><item><title>From Hacker to... Benefactor?</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/swamphacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 23:50:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/swamphacks/</guid><description>Last week, I went back to The University of Florida (UF) to recruit and represent Facebook as a corporate sponsor for SwampHacks (UF’s premier hackathon). As a former organizer of the event during my stint as a student, I was left feeling both humility and pride, seeing how far SwampHacks has come. During the early years of the event, we were lucky to have 200 attendees and had to basically beg sponsors to recognize the event as legitimate.</description></item><item><title>The Philosophy of a Dairy Pill</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/dairy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 14:14:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/dairy/</guid><description>Lactose Intolerance [ lak-tohs in-tol-er-uh ns ] / noun — a digestive disorder caused by the inability to digest lactose, a main carbohydrate in dairy products, which can lead to a negative effect on quality of life. A very common disorder, with some groups estimated to have a 79% rate of affliction.
It was a lovely, brisk Sunday evening in Seattle. Autumn was imminent, so the leaves had recently shifted to a more varied palette of rustic earth tones.</description></item><item><title>Sleep as a Service (SaaS)</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/sleep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 14:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/sleep/</guid><description>I recently finished Matthew Walker’s Why We Sleep, a New York Times Bestseller which has been exploding in the productivity-obsessed circles that I’m a part of. For good reason too — this book distills the vast amount of modern sleep research over the past 20 years into one main idea: sleep is really important. In the past year or so, I’ve been experimenting with everything in the sleep-improvement space, from blackout curtains to melatonin to timing my caffeine consumption (all of these being small but integral pieces of the puzzle).</description></item><item><title>2 Months of Solo Travel</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/2-months-of-solo-travel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 14:11:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/2-months-of-solo-travel/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nirvana in Thailand</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/nirvana-in-thailand/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 14:09:11 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/nirvana-in-thailand/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Exploring My Mind With Python</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/exploring-my-mind-with-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 22:11:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/exploring-my-mind-with-python/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Two Months in a Backpack</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/two-months-in-a-backpack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 22:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/two-months-in-a-backpack/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/digital-minimalism/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 18:11:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/digital-minimalism/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>