<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on Nikhil Thota</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on Nikhil Thota</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilthota.com/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Memex</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/projects/memex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/projects/memex/</guid><description>This was originally posted on my newsletter.
A few weeks ago I came across this tweet from Linus, better known as @thesephist:
NEW PROJECT — I made a &amp;quot;personal search engine&amp;quot; that lets me search all my blogs, tweets, journals, notes, contacts, &amp;amp; more at once 🚀
It&amp;#39;s called Monocle, and features a full text search system written in Ink 👇
GitHub ⌨️ https://t.co/XWtiCr5CmZ
Demo 🔍 https://t.co/8nhS8M3Du3 pic.twitter.com/rfurqpmaXc
&amp;mdash; Linus (@thesephist) July 8, 2021 Over a weekend, Linus collected a bunch of his personal data (blog posts, tweets, journal entries, etc.</description></item><item><title>Like Riding a Bike</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/riding-a-bike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/riding-a-bike/</guid><description>Something that has always astounded me is the vast amount of information tucked away in some corner of our minds, out of reach. We&amp;rsquo;ve all spent our entire lives engaged in some activity or another and provide our brains a constant stream of input. A small percentage of this input sticks, while most seemingly disappears. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t believe this data is completely gone — it&amp;rsquo;s merely hidden.
Biologically, our brains are complex and messy.</description></item><item><title>Lad Culture vs. Chad Culture</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/lad-culture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/lad-culture/</guid><description>A little while ago, I was on &amp;ldquo;holiday&amp;rdquo; in Madrid with some European friends from my exchange semester of University. During our reunion, my fellow American compatriot (Kevin) and I noticed there was a fundamentally different way that they approached time with friends, compared to hangouts in America. Enter Lad Culture.
Before I go any further, here are a few attributes of chads &amp;amp; lads to get us more aligned on definitions:</description></item><item><title>Work-Vacation Balance</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/work-vacation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/work-vacation/</guid><description>This was originally posted on my Hawaii Travel Journal.
&amp;hellip;
Our first few days in Kona were standard. We got some morning coffee, I rolled into work at 7am, grinded out some code, and clocked out by 3pm. The evenings were filled with walks, historic sites (more on hawaiian history here), and sunsets by the small beach near our Airbnb known as &amp;ldquo;Keiki Beach Queen&amp;rsquo;s Bath&amp;rdquo;.
By merging the energies of work and life in this way, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that I genuinely enjoy working on meaningful projects while on vacation.</description></item><item><title>Aquatic Confessions</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/water-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/water-1/</guid><description>This was originally posted on my newsletter.
I have a&amp;hellip; confession to make. I&amp;rsquo;m an adult that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to swim. I spent the majority of my childhood in one of America&amp;rsquo;s wettest states: Florida. As is tradition in the swamp, my parents put me in swim lessons. Though, my 8-year-old self decided that he preferred video games on land and my parents didn&amp;rsquo;t fight it, not knowing how to swim themselves.</description></item><item><title>A Self Experimentation Protocol</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/self-experimentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/self-experimentation/</guid><description>This was originally posted on my newsletter.
This past month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been chowing down on globs of spirulina, chlorella, and other nutritious micro-algae every day. I&amp;rsquo;m sane I swear — these algae are some of the most dense and bioavailable sources of protein &amp;amp; nutrients available. There is also some promising research showing that they might protect the brain and improve metabolic function.
A problem innate to health &amp;amp; nutrition research is that the human body is finicky, and what benefits one person will not necessarily benefit another.</description></item><item><title>Zen and The Art of Software Engineering</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/zen-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/zen-software-engineering/</guid><description>Originally posted on my newsletter.
One of the great ironies of life is that when you achieve something you&amp;rsquo;ve been working towards (e.g. get from point A to point B), you often feel empty and restless afterwards. It&amp;rsquo;s partially because of a post-dopamine release of prolactin, and partially because of an assumption that getting to B will solve your problems. The reality is that you ought to find a new B soon, or the lack of self-imposed structure will eat away at you.</description></item><item><title>The Discomfort Index</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/discomfort/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/notes/discomfort/</guid><description>This is an experiment. I refuse to be limited by the tantalizing decree to write something perfect or fully fleshed out every time I have an idea. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent months procrastinating on this piece because I felt like it had to be perfect, when something short and to the point would have sufficed.
When attempting something new, discomfort is unavoidable. From building an exercise routine to quitting a bad habit, discomfort is necessary.</description></item></channel></rss>