<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Nikhil Thota</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Nikhil Thota</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilthota.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beware of Unearned Wisdom</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/unearned-wisdom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/unearned-wisdom/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Art of Unemployment</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/art-of-unemployment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/art-of-unemployment/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Why I'm Addicted To Saunas</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sauna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sauna/</guid><description>tl;dr Sauna use has been shown to aid in pain relief, muscle recovery, deep sleep, mental health, immune function, cardiovascular performance, chronic inflammation, and longevity. One study showed that (in middle-aged Finnish men) using the sauna 4-7x a week decreased all-cause mortality by a whopping 40% versus 1x a week.1 If you want the most bang for your buck, the best effective dose of sauna usage (that has been rigorously researched) is 15-20 minutes at 180°F around 4-5 times a week — you just want to make sure you get a nice sweat going.</description></item><item><title>The Unsustainable Activity of New York City</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/unsustainable/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/unsustainable/</guid><description>“There is something in the New York air that makes sleep useless.”
— Simone de Beauvoir
On Visiting NYC Every trip I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to New York City (NYC) has been uniquely memorable. The city is constantly evolving, so it&amp;rsquo;s as if I&amp;rsquo;ve entered a new city, in a new era, on top of my own evolving perspective of the world. Here are a few memorable times:
My first trip in the city involved trouncing through Times Square while I scoured for Grand Central Station to take me to New Haven for a hackathon.</description></item><item><title>Facing Fears in Big Island</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/fears/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/fears/</guid><description>If you’d like to skip straight to my recommendations, please click here.
A few months ago, I went to Hawaii (again) with Mack during a beautiful interlude in-between jobs. This post is the first in what I hope will become a series of journal entries that dive into my travels. Here are a few goals for this maiden voyage:
First, I want to see if this is useful / enjoyable for myself and my readers (you).</description></item><item><title>On Anime and Manga アニメ</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/anime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/anime/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to skip to a tl;dr on what to know when trying to start watching anime, click here.
I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a trend with people that enjoy anime. Outside of the more passionate outliers, fans tend to underplay or even omit their love for the genre until someone else brings it up. With these people, conversations go somewhat like this:
comic creds: my funny 10 y/o sister Neha</description></item><item><title>What happens when you don’t eat for 72 hours?</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/fasting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/fasting/</guid><description>Alla Hetman
Hey everyone. Before we get into this, I am not a medical professional (sorry dad). Everything that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is based on personal experience and publicly available information. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering doing an extended fast, do your own research. ✌🏽
A couple of months ago, my marathon-running-roommate Kenton convinced me, my other roommate Tyler, and my girlfriend Mack to attempt a 72 hour fast with him. I&amp;rsquo;d been curious about fasting for a while but wanted to start with 24 hours and eventually work my way up to a full three days.</description></item><item><title>Multimodal Reading</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/multimodal-reading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/multimodal-reading/</guid><description>Books are incredible. They&amp;rsquo;re even better when you can get them for free. However, one thing that I struggle with is figuring out what to read with the vast quantity of options available. One thing that has helped me is segmenting my reading into buckets based on the medium of consumption.
What does that mean? Today, there are more ways to read a book than to just buy a physical tome and read it cover-to-cover.</description></item><item><title>The Sun and The Clouds</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sun-and-clouds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sun-and-clouds/</guid><description>Imagine that we live where it&amp;#39;s always cloudy. We never see the sun. And we, of course, take our everyday experience as if it&amp;#39;s reality—the only reality. The clouds are perhaps a little claustrophobic in some vague way but they&amp;#39;re comfortable and familiar. One day we meet a visitor who tells us that what we&amp;#39;re used to isn&amp;#39;t the whole story, that there&amp;#39;s something else. Curious, we go with him, and he guides us up a mountain.</description></item><item><title>Musings on Avatar and War</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/avatar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/avatar/</guid><description>Growing up we were taught that the Fire Nation was the greatest civilization in history. And somehow the war was our way of sharing our greatness with the rest of the world. What an amazing lie that was. The people of the world are terrified by the Fire Nation. They don&amp;#39;t see our greatness — They hate us! And we deserve it. We created an era of fear in the world.</description></item><item><title>Libby: Free Knowledge</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/libby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/libby/</guid><description>havin&amp;rsquo; fun ain&amp;rsquo;t hard&amp;hellip; if you got a library card
August 21st, 2019 was an interesting day for me. It was an average wednesday, except that I had just gotten an audiobook copy of When Breath Becomes Air by Paul Kalanithi. Being the 2x playback speed fiend that I am, I made it to the end in a couple of days and found myself tearing up in the gym in between sets of incline bench press.</description></item><item><title>The Untethered Soul</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/untethered-soul/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 23:50:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/untethered-soul/</guid><description>15808 NW 90th Street, Alachua, Florida, 32615 — The Temple of the Universe
Nested in the thicket of North Florida&amp;rsquo;s wilderness, about a 30 minute drive from the University of Florida, is the Temple of the Universe. The temple is a spiritual sanctuary where &amp;lsquo;men and women of any religion or set of beliefs can come together to experience the love, peace, and bliss which exists within all beings.&amp;rsquo; The temple was set up by Michael “Micky” Singer, an ex-entrepreneur who started a company that was acquired by WebMD for over $5 billion to focus fully on writing and spirituality.</description></item><item><title>Disjointed Fellowship Fragments</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/interact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 23:50:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/interact/</guid><description>A few months ago, I applied to the Interact Fellowship, but unfortunately got rejected shortly after. The application essays however, were incredibly insightful and posed a lot of interesting questions that I found myself thinking a lot about. I wanted to share my ramblings for some of these questions because I think that they tell a lot about who I am as a person. Shoutout to Kenton for the idea.</description></item><item><title>On Frugality and Flourishing</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/frugality-flourishing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 14:15:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/frugality-flourishing/</guid><description>It’s February, and I have a yearning to finally finish this piece. I’ve been putting it off for so long, but it’s time that I actually attempt to press some keys and create some prose. This is a topic I feel is especially relevant these days as I’ve been having interesting conversations and thoughts about money and the value of frugality. If my first several months into the world of true financial independence as a fully fledged ‘adult’ is any signal, I am obsessed with saving money.</description></item><item><title>From Hacker to... Benefactor?</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/swamphacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 23:50:08 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/swamphacks/</guid><description>Last week, I went back to The University of Florida (UF) to recruit and represent Facebook as a corporate sponsor for SwampHacks (UF’s premier hackathon). As a former organizer of the event during my stint as a student, I was left feeling both humility and pride, seeing how far SwampHacks has come. During the early years of the event, we were lucky to have 200 attendees and had to basically beg sponsors to recognize the event as legitimate.</description></item><item><title>The Philosophy of a Dairy Pill</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/dairy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 14:14:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/dairy/</guid><description>Lactose Intolerance [ lak-tohs in-tol-er-uh ns ] / noun — a digestive disorder caused by the inability to digest lactose, a main carbohydrate in dairy products, which can lead to a negative effect on quality of life. A very common disorder, with some groups estimated to have a 79% rate of affliction.
It was a lovely, brisk Sunday evening in Seattle. Autumn was imminent, so the leaves had recently shifted to a more varied palette of rustic earth tones.</description></item><item><title>Sleep as a Service (SaaS)</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sleep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 14:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/sleep/</guid><description>I recently finished Matthew Walker’s Why We Sleep, a New York Times Bestseller which has been exploding in the productivity-obsessed circles that I’m a part of. For good reason too — this book distills the vast amount of modern sleep research over the past 20 years into one main idea: sleep is really important. In the past year or so, I’ve been experimenting with everything in the sleep-improvement space, from blackout curtains to melatonin to timing my caffeine consumption (all of these being small but integral pieces of the puzzle).</description></item><item><title>2 Months of Solo Travel</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/2-months-solo-travel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 14:11:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/2-months-solo-travel/</guid><description>taipei night market
Travel, like life, is a marathon and not a race — somebody Globalism, smartphones, and balance. These were my topics of musing and reflection during my summer travels. I spent almost 2 months, in between my college graduation at the University of Florida and full-time employment at Facebook, bouncing between Europe and Southeast Asia with just a backpack. This somewhat-solo trip was unlike anything I’d ever done before, and as I’ve settled into a stable groove here in San Francisco, I’d like to unpack some of the personal and more broad-reaching insights I’ve gleaned.</description></item><item><title>Nirvana in Thailand</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/nirvana-in-thailand/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 14:09:11 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/nirvana-in-thailand/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I was going to write this as a satire piece poking fun at the wanderlust travel subculture but after this adventure, I genuinely feel like there’s something for me to explore in writing, so instead I am going to try and earnestly distill my experience into useful substance.
Pai is an interesting place, to say the least. Twenty years ago, the remote village in northern Thailand was nothing more than a small outpost inhabited by a few indigenous groups, sewn together by mountains, rice fields, and the flourishing Pai river.</description></item><item><title>Two Months in a Backpack</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/two-months-backpack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 22:11:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/two-months-backpack/</guid><description>This summer, I will be taking the quintessential millennial post-graduation pilgrimage to Southeast Asia for about two months. I wanted to optimize my travel experience as much as possible and this involves traveling with no luggage other than a backpack. I’ve spent a lot of time these past months procrastinating on school responsibilities by planning out this trip and along the way have learned a few things about efficient and intentional travel which I’d like to share.</description></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism</title><link>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/digital-minimalism/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 18:11:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nikhilthota.com/writing/digital-minimalism/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>